Miroslav Tushev

I am a PhD candidate (research assistant) in Computer Science and Engineering with 4+ years of experience in data analytics, seeking a data scientist position. I recently developed and published an unsupervised keyword-assisted topic modeling approach for modeling app user reviews in the top-1 conference in Software Engineering (ICSE'22). I am skilled in Python, predictive modeling, inferential and descriptive statistics, data scraping and visualization, and machine learning.

EXPERIENCE

Louisiana State University, Department of Computer Science and Engineering — Research Assistant

2018 - PRESENT

- Published 12 scientific papers in the most prestigious venues in the field of Software Engineering, developing practical solutions for improving software products.
- Helped my lead PI to secure 2 NSF grants worth \$210,000 to sponsor our research lab and graduate students for 3 years.
- Programmed a data scraping and code repository analysis tool in C# (10 kLOC) for GitHub Open Source projects. Published in 2 papers.
- Applied web data scraping libraries in Python to extract, clean, and organize datasets of mobile app reviews and Tweets for further analysis. Built end-to-end ML models.
- Posed hypotheses, applied statistical analysis, visualized data, and developed machine learning models to gain insights from massive datasets of user feedback.
- Authored and co-authored numerous papers, focusing on bug localization, modeling user concerns of mobile apps, classifying apps using word embeddings, and digital discrimination.

Louisiana State University, Department of Computer Science and Engineering — *Teaching Assistant*

2018 - 2020

- Designed and conducted an experiment to measure the impact of using GitHub as a student collaboration platform for group software projects.
- Independently supervised classes of 60-100 students (Numerical Methods with MATLAB and Intro to Java programming).
- Led LSU Pre-College Python summer camps for high-achieving K-12 students.

PROFILE Dhone

Phone +1 (225) 937-6341

miroslavtushev@gmail.com

Portfolio

github.com/miroslavtushev

Blog

miroslavtushev.medium.com

Personal Webpage miroslavtushev.com

EDUCATION

PhD in Computer Science Louisiana State University 2018 - 2022

MSc in Computer Science Louisiana State University 2016 - 2018

BSc in Management
The Russian Presidential
Academy of National
Economy and Public
Administration
2009 - 2014

SKILLS

Programming: Python, C#, Java, bash, CSS, JS, C.

Libraries: pandas, numpy, scikit-learn, scipy, spacy, NLTK, gensim, matplotlib, tensorflow.

Data Science: A/B testing, EDA, data scraping, wrangling, visualization, modeling, and interpretation, hypothesis testing, experimental design.

Misc: SQL, git, MS Excel.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- I blog about data science, statistics, and ML on Medium (miroslavtushev.medium.com).
- Served as a student volunteer for the International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE 2021).
- Maintained the official website and the social media accounts of the Crowd-Based Requirements Engineering Conference (CrowdRE 2020, 2021).
- Served as a reviewer for the International Conference on Mining Software Repositories (MSR).